Finding Aid for the Ralph J. Bunche Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
E. G. Rogers Collection
1932-1967
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0368
.42 linear_feet
Biography/History
E. G. Rogers received his MA Degree in 1936 from Peabody College for Teachers. He became an English Teacher, wrote for a local newspaper, and authored several books including a biography on Nathan Bedford Forrest. He was active in several organizations including the Tennessee Education Association, and the Tennessee Folklore Society. He served as a Counselor for the Poetry Society of Tennessee where he received a Gem Stone Award in 1967 for his poetry.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains 49 items: 45 letters, two poems, one biographical sketch, and one newspaper clipping. These items have been placed in 27 acid-free file folders, and will be stored in one Hollinger box totaling .165 linear feet.
The majority of the correspondence includes a typed biographical notation about the writer, and his relationship to him/her. It includes a biographical sketch written by Donald Davidson as well as two of his unpublished poems.
- Biographical Sketch - Davidson, Donald [by Donald Davidson]
- Correspondence - Incoming
  - Babin, J. P. (Poetry Society of Tennessee), September 23, 1967
  - Beaudoin, Kenneth L., May 6, 1967
  - Bradley, Mary Forrest [with biographical notation], May 29, 1934
  - Claxton, P. P., February 27, 1939
  - Cope, Quill E., February 10, 1954
  - Crabb, A. L., March 11, 1961
  - Curry, Walter Clyde, March 2, 1939
  - Davidson, Donald [with biographical notation], February 2, 1932
  - April 9, 1934
  - April 12, 1934
  - February 14, 1935
  - April 1, 1937
  - February 20, 1939
  - June 12, 1942
  - May 15, 1944
  - November 14, 1944
  - Dromgoole, Will Allen, January 29, 1932
  - Edwards, Lawrence, March 8, 1950
  - Goodpasture, Henry, May 7, 1964
  - August 20, 1964
  - Henry, Robert S. [with biographical notation], January 8, 1934
  - March 31, 1936
  - October 16, 1944
  - Holt, A. D., December 23, 1938
  - Hull, Cordell, September 21, 1943
  - Jackson, George Pullen [with biographical notation], July 2, 1947
  - James, Marquis [with biographical notation], September 14, 1933
  - May 4, 1940
  - Johnson, James Weldon [with biographical notation], April 26, 1932
  - May 5, 1937
  - Jones, Carter Helm [with biographical notation], September 18, 1934
  - September 28, 1934
  - November 16, 1934
  - n.d.
  - Merchant, Jane [with biographical notation], December 18, 1957
  - Parker, Roscoe E., November 8, 1939
  - Pendleton, Charles S. [with biographical notation], January 4, 1936
  - January 13, 1936
  - August 20, 1938
  - January 18, 1939
  - Stokely, Wilma Dykeman [with biographical notation], April 12, 1956
  - October 26, 1960
  - Stuart, Jesse [with biographical notation], October 8, 1936
  - May 6, 1937
  - May 27, 1949
- Newspaper Clipping
  - May 17, 1967
- Poems
  - Country Music – by Donald Davidson [inscribed and signed, not dated]
  - The Mustering, 1867 – by Donald Davidson [inscribed and signed, not dated]